Alone in this house, I have watched the seasons slip past...
until this flower finally blossomed here.
How I've longed to see your beautifully clear eyes and hear your tender voice...
I have always known.
I have always known that a magnificent flower would blossom here.
I'm so happy.
Lord Hikaru... Master Genji...
When will you visit next?
Three months have passed since our last meeting.
Please return within the month this time.
No, ten days... five days... or even tomorrow!
Forgive me, I forget myself.
You have many lovers in the capital.
I have made such an unseemly request.
I shall return forthwith. As soon as I can.
It would be remiss of me to let another pluck such a radiant flower.
Koremitsu. Koremitsu.
Yes, sir.
I am here. How may I be of service?
Send a gift to that lady. More splendid than the usual.
As you wish, sir.
Who knows what tomorrow may bring?
I do not know when I shall next visit.
Very good, sir.
Episode 1
Master Hikaru
I don't have a concept prepared for today either
kyou mo konseputo nanka moukenai wa
No matter what happens, I won't run away
donna hapuningu datte kawasanai wa
Talent
sainou
Skill
yuunou
My brain's pleasure center
gouyuudainou
My senses
kannou
Go to the front lines! Your signal is clear
ike saizensen! anata no aizu kaimei
I'm at an age where I want to choose my own vague sympathies
aimai mimai erabitai toshigoro
Give me more difficult topics
motto nandai wo watashi ni dashite
Well done!
I only prefer colors that I can taste right now
tatta ima shika ajiwaenai iro ga ii no
Tell me about this moment as much as you can
ima no saidagen wo kikasete!
Well done!
Lets meet up so we can use up the present
tatta ima tsukaihatasu tame no aouyo
Hello!
I say, if it isn't Master Hikaru...
Are you out for a stroll admiring the peak of the cherry blossom season?
Hm? Yes, I suppose I am.
The cherry blossoms of the capital.
Or perhaps I should call it the crowning point of spring...
Some trees covered in splendor; others stripped by the wind.
They truly are myriad, are they not?
Y-Yes.
And which do you prefer, Master Hikaru?
Excuse my impertinence.
However, if the idle gossip among the ladies of the Imperial Court is to be believed,
you certainly have an impressive reputation as a man who has stripped a few boughs.
You're a fine one to talk, Lord Tou no Chuujou.
I have heard similar rumors about you from the ladies-in-waiting.
About me, you say? What on Earth could you mean?
That wherever Lord Chuujou treads, even a tree that is wilting shall burst into full bloom.
Ah? Surely not.
Let's just say that the spring air invites the people to gossip.
Let us leave it at that, shall we?
This is his story, the one called Master Genji.
He, whose story has been told and retold.
Ephemeral romance.
Tumultuous passion.
Each tale must be told in turn.
For in each and every tale is a testament to the love in his life.
He was very young when he experienced his first love.
Snow flurries were dancing in the wind on a winter morning.
A quiet pond, rarely visited, away from the Imperial Palace.
As a child, Lord Hikaru favored this place to savor his solitude.
Who are you?
Who are you...?
Who... are you?
Princess? Are you there?
Where are you?
Who are you?
Who was that?
Who was that beautiful woman?
That was how it all began.
The nine-year-old Lord Hikaru.
And the fourteen-year-old Fujitsubo of the Wisteria Pavilion.
Oh, my. Young master. How may we assist you?
No, I require nothing.
Lord Hikaru, are you in search of someone?
N-No!
Lord Hikaru was the Emperor's second son.
His mother, of whom he had no memory, was Kiritsubo.
The Lady of the Paulownia Pavilion, who was not long for this world.
The Emperor adored her more than anyone; she was a woman said to be transcendently beautiful.
Her story is told even now.
For that reason, the Emperor was fond of Master Hikaru.
Indeed, he gave him the surname Genji, and made him a high retainer in the court.
Note: By giving Genji a last name, the Emperor is making him a commoner, removing him from the imperial line of succession.
If the Emperor were to pass away, Genji would undoubtedly become a pawn...
in the court's political infighting to name a successor to the throne.
It is said that the Emperor's desire...
to spare Lord Hikaru of that cruel fate compelled him to name the boy a commoner.
Lord Hikaru? Young master?
Were you standing by the pond again?
I searched everywhere for you.
Here. Your formal court garb.
Your father... the Emperor wishes to see you.
Why?
It seems as though there is someone he wishes to make your acquaintance.
I don't want to meet anyone.
That won't do, saying such selfish things. You mustn't.
Master Hikaru?
It might be her!
Enter, Hikaru.
This is Lady Fujitsubo.
I knew it! It's her! I've finally found her!
From this day forward, she will be my wife.
In other words, I would like you to think of her as your new mother.
So you're Master Hikaru!
I am delighted to meet you, Master Hikaru.
Yes.
Do you like illustrated stories?
Y-Yes.
Come!
Come with me.
I have brought a number of scrolls with me.
Look.
And look at this one too!
I've heard this one before! It's about a monster!
He has a horrifying face, but underneath, he has a compassionate heart.
Yes, that's the one!
The Emperor appears to be in fine spirits.
How truly fortunate he met Lady Fujitsubo.
It was destined to be - she is the very image of Master Hikaru's mother, Lady Kiritsubo.
That's true. When they play together, it is akin to watching a mother with her child.
Not at all. Fujitsubo is yet young; he is more like a younger brother to her.
Spring?
At this time every year, I begin to look forward to spring.
Spring...
Spring is so joyous.
Blooming plum blossoms, the scent of peach blossoms,
and rows of cherry blossoms everywhere.
Everything becomes so bright and lustrous.
Now that this is my home, it's strange to think that...
I will miss the moment spring comes to my own garden this year.
Do you miss it?
Your home?
You do, don't you?
No, that's not true.
The Emperor is so kind and you have also welcomed me into your life.
Oh dear, why am I crying?
Something must be the matter with me.
I am fine. Really.
It hurts... It hurts sometimes, but I'm fine.
Lord Hikaru? Young master?
It's frightfully cold tonight.
Please retire to your chamber and rest.
Lord Hikaru?
Do not worry. I shall wait here.
Look over there. Spring is about to arrive.
I want to witness its arrival with my own eyes.
I want to see the way spring adorns that branch so that I can tell her about it.
Tell whom?
Whom do you wish to tell?
Is it Lady Fujitsubo?
Master Hikaru?
Spring is so late this year.
He fell in!
Master Hikaru has fallen in the pond!
He has fallen while gathering flowers!
I'm sorry.
I dropped the first flowers of spring in the pond.
I knew it.
What?
You wished to gather them for me, did you not?
Thank you.
But please do not.
In future, please refrain from placing yourself in harm's way for my sake.
I will grow bigger... and stronger...
Pardon?
Then shall I be able to grant you anything you desire. I shall be able to protect you.
Thank you, kind Master Hikaru.
When you are older, I know that you will become a magnificent gentleman.
I look forward to it.
My, my, Master Hikaru! What beautiful handwriting!
The Emperor is always boasting about his son's masterful brush.
Of course, he doesn't leave out your excellent horsemanship and archery, either.
I had a dream this morning.
It's the same dream as always, but this time, there were differences.
I dreamed of my mother's passing.
Your mother, Lady Kiritsubo?
Yes. However, this morning, her face looked just like yours.
I apologize.
Worry not.
Fate sent me to replace your mother.
This dream must be proof of that.
I am like an older sister to you...
and you are my younger brother and child.
Is that not poignant?
You are not my mother, nor my sister.
You are... you are my...
After that, the springs came and went.
As time passed, that moment remained a secret; not a soul knew of it.
Master Hikaru matured and grew ever more handsome.
There were ladies in the court who wrote love letters praising his beauty, while others wrote poems.
And yet, Master Hikaru would always visit one place over all others:
Lady Fujitsubo's pavilion.
He spent his days flitting back and forth to visit her.
I have brought you a handful of wisteria blossoms.
I heard that you are suffering from a cold. I thought these might lift your spirits, Lady Fujitsubo.
Please leave them there. I would not wish to spread my illness to you.
Could you please allow me to rest today?
Of course. I only came to deliver the flowers.
Please take care.
I shall perhaps meet with you tomorrow, then.
This is the correct path. This is how it must be.
I must distance myself from him, little by little.
It is unthinkable... I want him to understand that these feelings are unthinkable.
Strong... I must be strong.
If I endure,
he shall forget all of this.
Hikaru turned twelve...
and came of age.
Coming of age means to be recognized by the world as an adult for the first time.
At the same time, it marked the day that Lady Fujitsubo had long awaited.
A day that had finally arrived.
The strict decorum of the Imperial Court stated...
that a mature adult was subject to the Emperor,
as was his correspondence with the ladies and ladies-in-waiting.
He would not be permitted to even set foot in the same chamber as her.
I implore you... please lift your blind.
Let me see your face one last time.
I bid you farewell.
By the way, Master Genji...
I have oft noticed a peculiar look in your eyes.
As though you are gazing at something far off, yet not seeing anything at all.
Yes... those eyes.
As though you're wholly adrift in an unrequited love too intense to bear.
Is this another of your deductions?
Forgive me.
How could any fair maiden possibly resist the charms of the greatest lover to ever walk the Earth?
Truthfully, Master Hikaru's heart still cherished the love that blossomed on that secret day so long ago.
I wish you would have turned around at least once
semete ichido kurai furimuite hoshikatta
I wish I could have stayed by your side like the wind
semete kaze no you ni tada soba ni utakatta
I locked away my feelings for you
ichizuma omoi ni kagi wo kake
But, even to this day, my imprisoned heart still smells sweet
tojikometa kokoro wa, ima mo mada amaku kaoru
I always had my gaze upon only you
anato wo anata dake wo itsu demo muteimashita
This unrequited love was like a flower that can never bloom
sakanai tsubomi no you ni mukuwarenai koi deshita